<entry>
    <id>3438</id>
    <title>Moving from Spending to Investment: A Research Agenda for Improving Health Care Financing
      for Children and Youth with Special Health Care Needs</title>
    <status>publish</status>
    <created>2022-06-03 21:08:12</created>
    <changed>2022-06-06 18:08:24</changed>
    <field_event_date>2022-06-22 10:00:00</field_event_date>
    <field_file />
    <field_focus_area>Systems and Standards</field_focus_area>
    <field_image>
      <image>
        <alt></alt>
        <title></title>
        <filename>webinar_flier.png</filename>
      </image>
    </field_image>
    <field_link>
      <item>
        <field_link_url>https://lpfch.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_EWyzknKWT76KX8d8G9mxwA</field_link_url>
        <field_link_title>Learn More and Register</field_link_title>
        <field_link_attributes>a:1:{s:6:"target";s:6:"_blank";}</field_link_attributes>
      </item>
    </field_link>
    <field_location_ref></field_location_ref>
    <field_speakers>
      <item>
        <id>290</id>
        <field_full_name>Dennis Kuo, MD, MHS</field_full_name>
        <field_image>
          <image>
            <alt></alt>
            <title></title>
            <filename>dennis_z_kuo.jpg</filename>
          </image>
        </field_image>
        <field_job_title>Associate Professor, University at Buffalo, Division Chief of General
          Pediatrics, UBMD Pediatrics, and Attending Physician, Oishei Children&#x2019;s Hospital</field_job_title>
        <field_teaser>&lt;p&gt;Dennis Kuo is a primary care pediatrician with a special interest in
          children with disabilities and medical complexity.&amp;nbsp; His academic work focuses on
          family-centered care and family-identified health care needs of children with medical
          complexity, and more recently evolved to care coordination design and health care system
          reform. Dr. Kuo&#x2019;s prior work funded by the Health Resources and Services
          Administration includes the Arkansas System of Care State Implementation Grant for
          Children with Special Health Care Needs, the Maternal and Child Health Research grant, and
          the Early Childhood Comprehensive Systems project.&amp;nbsp; He is the current Chair of
          the American Academy of Pediatrics Council on Children with Disabilities (COCWD),
          following six years of serving on the Executive Committee of the COCWD, and he is a member
          of the Board of Directors of Family Voices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
</field_teaser>
      </item>
      <item>
        <id>291</id>
        <field_full_name>Margaret (Meg) Comeau, MHA</field_full_name>
        <field_image>
          <image>
            <alt></alt>
            <title></title>
            <filename>meg_c.jpg</filename>
          </image>
        </field_image>
        <field_job_title>Senior Project Director, Center for Innovation in Social Work &amp; Health
          at Boston University</field_job_title>
        <field_teaser>&lt;p&gt;Meg Comeau is a nationally recognized expert on the impact of
          Medicaid and federal health care reform on children with complex care needs. She brings
          more than 15 years of health care delivery and financing experience to her role as
          principal investigator for the Collaborative Improvement and Innovation Network (CoIIN) to
          Advance Care for Children with Medical Complexity and as co-principal investigator of the
          Catalyst Center, a project focused on insurance coverage for children and youth with
          special health care needs. Meg is a member of the Leadership Circle for the Institute for
          Professionalism and Ethical Practice (IPEP) at Boston Children&#x2019;s Hospital and also
          serves as faculty for IPEP&#x2019;s Program to Enhance Relational and Communication
          Skills.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
</field_teaser>
      </item>
      <item>
        <id>292</id>
        <field_full_name>Jeff Schiff, MD, MBA </field_full_name>
        <field_image>
          <image>
            <alt></alt>
            <title></title>
            <filename>schiff_photo.jpg</filename>
          </image>
        </field_image>
        <field_job_title>Senior Scholar, AcademyHealth</field_job_title>
        <field_teaser>&lt;p&gt;Jeff Schiff is committed to creating an equitable patient and
          family-centered learning heath care system. He served as the Chief Medical Officer for
          Minnesota Human Services (Medicaid) from 2006-2019. In 2009 he was co-chair of the Agency
          for Healthcare Research and Quality committee that created the first national set of
          Medicaid core measures for children. In delivery system redesign he helped develop the
          Minnesota health care home program and the accountable care organization. Dr. Schiff is a
          past chair of the Medicaid Medical Directors Network and a former president of the
          Minnesota Chapter of the American Academy of Pediatrics. He is a pediatrician and
          emergency medicine physician.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
          &#xD;
          &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
</field_teaser>
      </item>
      <item>
        <id>293</id>
        <field_full_name>Christopher Stille, MD, MPH</field_full_name>
        <field_image>
          <image>
            <alt></alt>
            <title></title>
            <filename>stille_formal_picture_9-14.jpg</filename>
          </image>
        </field_image>
        <field_job_title>Professor of Pediatrics and Section Head of General Academic Pediatrics,
          University of Colorado School of Medicine and Children&#x2019;s Hospital Colorado</field_job_title>
        <field_teaser>&lt;p&gt;Christopher Stille leads a group of 50 pediatric faculty, practices
          and teaches primary care pediatrics, and conducts pediatric health services research and
          quality improvement efforts focused on improving systems of care for children and youth
          with special health care needs (CYSHCN) in the medical home. His research is focused on
          improving communication and coordinated care for CYSHCN between primary care clinicians,
          subspecialists, and family caregivers. He is also the Principal Investigator of a Maternal
          and Child Health Bureau-funded national network to conduct health systems research for
          CYSHCN. Dr. Stille is a co-chair of the Standing Committee on Patient Experience and
          Function of the National Quality Forum. Additionally, he is a member of the Executive
          Committee of the Council on Children with Disabilities of the American Academy of
          Pediatrics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
</field_teaser>
      </item>
    </field_speakers>
    <field_teaser>&lt;p&gt;Children and youth with special health care needs are high utilizers of
      health care resources and their unique needs merit targeted consideration. The focus of
      payment reform efforts to date has been on adults with chronic illnesses, with less priority
      given to investment in children's health and the life course. Family leaders and researchers
      from across the country partnered to develop a national research agenda focused on improving
      the health care system for children and youth with special health care needs (CYSHCN). Their
      article titled &lt;a href="/node/3402"&gt;Moving from Spending to Investment: A Research
      Agenda for Improving Health Care Financing for Children and Youth With Special Health Care
      Needs&lt;/a&gt;, is one in an eight-part series published as a supplement to
      &lt;em&gt;Academic Pediatrics&lt;/em&gt;. In this webinar, the article&#x2019;s authors will
      describe their study's findings, and present potential research topics to address the gaps in
      investing in children&#x2019;s health. We suggest that attendees read the article prior to the
      webinar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
      &#xD;
      &lt;p&gt;This work is led by the Children and Youth with Special Health Care Needs Research
      Network (CYSHCNet). CYSHCNet was founded in 2017 through a cooperative agreement with the
      Health Resources and Services Administration&#x2019;s Maternal and Child Health
      Bureau.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
      &#xD;
      &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
</field_teaser>
    <body></body>
  </entry>
