<entry>
    <id>1063</id>
    <title> Elizabeth and Bruce Dunlevie Donate $80 Million to Improve the Health of Mothers and
      Babies</title>
    <status>publish</status>
    <created>2021-02-12 21:30:02</created>
    <changed>2021-07-02 18:27:28</changed>
    <body>&lt;p&gt;Elizabeth and Bruce Dunlevie have made an $80 million gift to Lucile Packard
      Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Stanford and the Stanford University School of Medicine to
      launch a bold new clinical and research program that will transform the health of mothers and
      babies. The gift will help advance the science and practice of maternal-fetal medicine, and
      fund new facilities to increase access to care.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our
      family has been fortunate to live and work in Silicon Valley and in close proximity to
      Stanford for several decades, and we&amp;rsquo;ve been grateful beneficiaries of the excellent
      care delivered by Packard Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital more than once,&amp;rdquo; says Bruce
      Dunlevie. &amp;ldquo;Knowing from personal experience how transformative world-class medical
      treatment can be for mothers and babies, we&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to help advance the state of
      the art in medical science for maternal-fetal research, and to give every mother and baby the
      highest-quality medical care.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This gift represents an
      opportunity of a lifetime,&amp;rdquo; says Yasser El-Sayed, MD, division chief of
      maternal-fetal medicine and obstetrics at the School of Medicine and obstetrician-in-chief at
      Packard Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital. &amp;ldquo;Our team at Stanford and Packard will put
      our hearts and souls into building the most dynamic, productive, and innovative program
      possible&amp;mdash;one that fully leverages the new facility and translates discoveries into
      clinical impact for families locally and globally.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;A Legacy of
      Mothers Helping Mothers&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Packard Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital was founded
      on the vision of one mother, Lucile Salter Packard, who believed in the importance of caring
      for expectant mothers and their babies together. More than 100,000 babies have been born at
      the hospital since its 1991 opening. The Dunlevies&amp;rsquo; gift builds on Mrs.
      Packard&amp;rsquo;s legacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My journey with this hospital started
      as the mother of a child who needed life-saving care, and my family is forever grateful for
      Lucile&amp;rsquo;s vision and the care teams who ensured this hospital was here for us when we
      needed it,&amp;rdquo; says Elizabeth Dunlevie, who is board chair at the Lucile Packard
      Foundation for Children&amp;rsquo;s Health and a board member at Packard Children&amp;rsquo;s
      Hospital. &amp;ldquo;For all of us, the year 2020 has driven home the importance of health, of
      providing a healthy start for all families. With this gift we want to help ensure access to
      Packard&amp;rsquo;s quality of care for all mothers and babies, across socioeconomic
      boundaries, now and in the future.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The impact of this
      incredible gift will be felt for generations&amp;mdash;for the mothers and babies we help and,
      perhaps even more importantly, for those we will never have to treat because of new
      discoveries and cures made possible by this investment,&amp;rdquo; says Paul King, president
      and CEO of Packard Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Stanford Children&amp;rsquo;s Health.
      &amp;ldquo;My heart is full knowing that Elizabeth and Bruce&amp;rsquo;s gift embodies Lucile
      Packard&amp;rsquo;s intent for this hospital to be both a leading academic medical center as
      well as a community hospital available to all who need us.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;A New
      Home for Labor and Delivery&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2017, Packard Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital
      opened its new Main building, which serves most of the hospital&amp;rsquo;s pediatric
      patients. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to reimagine the beloved original building, known as the
      West building, as the primary home for services for mothers and babies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The
      Dunlevies&amp;rsquo; gift provides $50 million to launch a transformation of the 1st floor.
      Over the next few years, the hospital will build a new state-of-the-art labor and delivery
      unit with 14 private suites. For mothers requiring hospitalization prior to delivery, the
      hospital will also build a dedicated maternity antepartum unit. The new units will enhance the
      patient experience while supporting the most complex maternal and fetal
      care.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project is just the beginning. The Dunlevies&amp;rsquo;
      gift kick-starts an ambitious renewal throughout the West building. The Lucile Packard
      Foundation for Children&amp;rsquo;s Health is seeking additional philanthropic support to
      expand and enhance the neonatal intensive care units and postpartum maternity rooms in the
      coming years.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Through Elizabeth and
      Bruce&amp;rsquo;s profound commitment, we will be able to learn more, move faster, and make a
      bigger difference for the sickest mothers and babies,&amp;rdquo; says Cynthia Brandt, PhD,
      president and CEO of the Lucile Packard Foundation for Children&amp;rsquo;s Health.
      &amp;ldquo;They are setting an example of true philanthropy, of love and concern for others.
      As we launch a fundraising campaign for mothers and babies, we hope that many more community
      members will join us in this important mission.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Advancing the
      Science of Maternal-Fetal Medicine&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dunlevies&amp;rsquo; gift
      also provides $30 million to further develop a world-class Maternal-Fetal Medicine program at
      the School of Medicine. The hospital already treats complex fetal disorders. Yet with nearly
      two-thirds of the expectant mothers at Packard Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital being high-risk,
      there is potential to do more for mothers with underlying conditions such as heart disease,
      cancer, epilepsy, and diabetes, and for pressing obstetrical issues including preterm labor,
      placenta accreta, hemorrhage, and cesarean delivery prevention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The program
      will recruit additional faculty to accelerate discovery&amp;mdash;starting from basic science
      to understand the earliest part of human development, translating findings from the lab into
      clinical care, and disseminating strategies to improve maternal outcomes across California,
      the nation, and the globe.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In our mission to advance
      precision health, there is no better place to start than at the beginning,&amp;rdquo; says
      Lloyd Minor, MD, the Carl and Elizabeth Naumann Dean of the School of Medicine.
      &amp;ldquo;During the crucial period from pre-conception through pregnancy and a
      baby&amp;rsquo;s first days, we have the opportunity to improve the trajectory of entire
      lives. So many families will benefit from the people, programs, and facilities that will
      receive support from the Dunlevies&amp;rsquo; visionary
      gift.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are so fortunate to have Elizabeth and Bruce
      as long-standing champions of Stanford University, Stanford Medicine, and Packard
      Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital,&amp;rdquo; says Marc Tessier-Lavigne, president of Stanford
      University. &amp;ldquo;Their wisdom and hard work are invaluable to advancing our shared
      missions to improve human health. In these deeply challenging times, the Dunlevies&amp;rsquo;
      philanthropy provides welcome hope for the well-being of current and future generations. We
      are immensely grateful.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bruce has served on the Board of Trustees
      of Stanford University and as chairman of the board of the Stanford Management Company. As
      chair of the public spaces task force at Packard Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, Elizabeth
      shaped the family-friendly artwork, gardens, and experiential details of the Main building as
      well as recent updates in the West building. The Dunlevies&amp;rsquo; prior gifts to Packard
      Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Stanford Medicine have included generous investments for the
      Vera Moulton Wall Center for Pulmonary Vascular Disease, the Dunlevie Family Professorship in
      Pediatrics, the Dwight and Vera Dunlevie Professorship in Pediatric Cardiology, the Elizabeth
      Wood Dunlevie Professorship, and the Dunlevie
      Garden.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br
      /&gt;Jennifer Yuan | Lucile Packard Foundation for Children&amp;rsquo;s Health&amp;nbsp;&lt;br
      /&gt;(650) 799-6948 | &lt;a href="mailto:Jennifer.Yuan@lpfch.org
      "&gt;Jennifer.Yuan@lpfch.org&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About
      the Lucile Packard Foundation for Children&amp;rsquo;s Health&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The
      Lucile Packard Foundation for Children&amp;rsquo;s Health is a public charity, founded in
      1997. Its mission is to elevate the priority of children&amp;rsquo;s health, and to increase
      the quality and accessibility of children&amp;rsquo;s health care through leadership and
      direct investment. The Foundation works in alignment with Lucile Packard Children&amp;rsquo;s
      Hospital Stanford and the child health programs of the Stanford University School of Medicine.
      Learn more at &lt;a href="http://lpfch.org" target="_blank"&gt;lpfch.org&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
      href="http://supportLPCH.org"&gt;supportLPCH.org.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About
      Stanford Children&amp;rsquo;s Health&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stanford Children&amp;rsquo;s
      Health, with &lt;a
      href="https://www.stanfordchildrens.org/en/lucile-packard-childrens-hospital"
      target="_blank"&gt;Lucile Packard Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital Stanford&lt;/a&gt; at its
      center, is the Bay Area&amp;rsquo;s largest health care system exclusively dedicated to
      children and expectant mothers. Our network of care includes more than 65 &lt;a
      href="https://www.stanfordchildrens.org/en/locations-directions"
      target="_blank"&gt;locations&lt;/a&gt; across Northern California and more than 85 locations
      in the U.S. Western region. As part of &lt;a href="http://med.stanford.edu/"
      target="_blank"&gt;Stanford Medicine,&lt;/a&gt; a leading academic health system that also
      includes Stanford Health Care and Stanford University School of Medicine, we are cultivating
      the next generation of medical professionals and are at the forefront of scientific research
      to improve children&amp;rsquo;s health outcomes around the world. We are a nonprofit
      organization committed to supporting the community through meaningful outreach programs and
      services and providing necessary medical care to families, regardless of their ability to pay.
      Discover more at &lt;a href="http://stanfordchildrens.org"
      target="_blank"&gt;stanfordchildrens.org.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</body>
    <field_blog_author></field_blog_author>
    <field_blog_date></field_blog_date>
    <field_blog_images>
      <image>
        <alt></alt>
        <title>Bruce and Elizabeth Dunlevie have made an $80 million gift to Lucile Packard
          Children&#x2019;s Hospital Stanford and the Stanford University School of Medicine to
          facilitate the launch of a bold new clinical and research program that will transform the
          health of mothers and babies. (Credit: Lucile Packard Foundation for Children&#x2019;s
          Health)</title>
        <filename>dunlevie_closeup.jpg</filename>
      </image>
      <image>
        <alt></alt>
        <title>The West building of Lucile Packard Children&#x2019;s Hospital Stanford will be
          reimagined as the primary home for services for mothers and babies. The Dunlevies&#x2019;
          gift funds new facilities on the 1st floor. (Credit: Douglas Peck / Lucile Packard
          Children&#x2019;s Hospital Stanford)</title>
        <filename>west_building.jpg</filename>
      </image>
      <image>
        <alt></alt>
        <title>Yasser El-Sayed, MD, leads the maternal-fetal medicine program at the Stanford
          University School of Medicine. (Credit: Lucile Packard Children&#x2019;s Hospital
          Stanford)</title>
        <filename>yasser.jpg</filename>
      </image>
      <image>
        <alt></alt>
        <title>The Dunlevies&#x2019; gift will transform care and outcomes for mothers and babies.
          (Credit: Lucile Packard Foundation for Children&#x2019;s Health)</title>
        <filename>ali_kanoa.jpg</filename>
      </image>
      <image>
        <alt></alt>
        <title>The Dunlevies&#x2019; gift funds the construction of 14 new state-of-the-art suites
          for Labor and Delivery, to be located on the 1st floor of Packard Children&#x2019;s
          Hospital&#x2019;s West building. (Credit: Lucile Packard Children&#x2019;s Hospital
          Stanford)</title>
        <filename>labor_delivery.jpg</filename>
      </image>
      <image>
        <alt></alt>
        <title>A mother&#x2019;s journey at Labor and Delivery will begin with a welcoming entry.
          (Credit: Lucile Packard Children&#x2019;s Hospital Stanford)</title>
        <filename>front_desk.jpg</filename>
      </image>
      <image>
        <alt></alt>
        <title>The Dunlevies&#x2019; gift funds the construction of nine new private Maternity
          Antepartum rooms, to be located on the 1st floor of Packard Children&#x2019;s
          Hospital&#x2019;s West building. (Credit: Lucile Packard Children&#x2019;s Hospital
          Stanford)</title>
        <filename>room.jpg</filename>
      </image>
      <image>
        <alt></alt>
        <title>The new Labor and Delivery unit will include three operating rooms for cesarean
          delivery. (Credit: Lucile Packard Children&#x2019;s Hospital Stanford)</title>
        <filename>operating.jpg</filename>
      </image>
    </field_blog_images>
    <field_blog_related_blog_posts>976|787|669</field_blog_related_blog_posts>
    <field_blog_sidebar_elements>
      <item>
        <id>1019</id>
        <field_sidebar_element_body>Show your support for our patients and families by making a gift
          today.</field_sidebar_element_body>
        <field_sidebar_element_link>
          <item>
            <field_sidebar_element_link_url>supportLPCH.org/Donate</field_sidebar_element_link_url>
            <field_sidebar_element_link_title>Donate Now</field_sidebar_element_link_title>
            <field_sidebar_element_link_attributes>a:0:{}</field_sidebar_element_link_attributes>
          </item>
        </field_sidebar_element_link>
        <field_sidebar_title>How You Can Help</field_sidebar_title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <id>1020</id>
        <field_sidebar_element_body>Share your connection to Lucile Packard Children's Hospital
          Stanford.</field_sidebar_element_body>
        <field_sidebar_element_link>
          <item>
            <field_sidebar_element_link_url>https://supportlpch.org/blog/share-your-story</field_sidebar_element_link_url>
            <field_sidebar_element_link_title>SHARE NOW</field_sidebar_element_link_title>
            <field_sidebar_element_link_attributes>a:0:{}</field_sidebar_element_link_attributes>
          </item>
        </field_sidebar_element_link>
        <field_sidebar_title>Share your Story</field_sidebar_title>
      </item>
    </field_blog_sidebar_elements>
    <field_blog_tags>In the News|Donor Stories|Press Release|Major Gifts</field_blog_tags>
  </entry>
